[engine revving]
[Jerry] This is
a 1960 Rolls-Royce Silver Cloud II.
It has a 6.2-liter, V8 engine.
The horsepower is listed as "adequate."
It has a very elegant turning radius
of 42 feet.
[brakes screech]
[phone ringing]
-[Carl] Hello?
-[Jerry] Carl?
-[Carl] Yeah?
-It's Jerry.
[Carl] Oh, Jerry! Yes, yes. How are you?
[Jerry] I was in the area. I was wondering
if you would like to grab a coffee.
[Carl] You know something?
I was just about to have breakfast.
-You caught me at a perfect time.
-Fantastic, I'll be by in a few minutes.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
My very special guests today
are comedy legends Carl Reiner
and his pal of 62 years, Mel Brooks.
A long time ago, a guy came up
to me and he said,
"Can you give me a buck for a sandwich?"
And I said, "I'll give you a buck
if you promise me one thing."
He says, "What?"
I said, "You go get a drink.
'Cause you look like you can use a drink."
-[Jerry] What do you think of it?
-It is beautiful.
As a car, it's horrible.
-Really?
-Yeah. But it's a nice living room.
-Yeah.
-With wheels.
[car roaring]
-Was that your car making that noise?
-Yeah.
Wow, this is not very elegant.
I bet you nobody knows
that the first four episodes of Seinfeld
were shot on the same stage
as The Dick Van Dyke Show.
-I remember that.
-Remember that?
-I remember coming...
-I think you came and visited.
The very first show.
[Carl] Have a breakfast menu?
What could they possibly have on the menu
that you're not aware of?
How many breakfasts have you had?
-[Carl] No, I want to check the prices.
-Oh.
[Ruthie] My name is Ruthie
and I'll be your server.
-We're gonna be your eaters.
-[Ruthie] Oh, okay!
I'm gonna have soft scrambled eggs
and very, very crisp bacon.
So crisp that you'll say,
"That's too crisp." That's it.
And I'll have orange juice and coffee.
A cup of coffee.
-Mel comes over every night.
-Every night.
How long is that relationship?
[Carl] From 1950 on.
-So that's...
-[both] 62 years.
First day I met him,
he got up and did a Jewish pirate.
Hysterical.
You know, he said, "I can't afford
to pillage and rape anymore.
Three dollars and 50 cents
for a sailcloth! Who can afford that?"
He went on. And the following day,
I came in and said,
"Here's a man who was at the scene
of the Crucifixion 2,000 years ago,"
and I started to interview the 2,000--
Because he had done the pirate,
so you went back even further.
Yeah. I said,
"Here's a man who knows everything."
[Jerry] Okay, so Mel comes over.
About what time at night
would you say he gets there?
-Eight o'clock to eat--
-And what do you guys watch?
We like a movie if somebody says,
"Secure the perimeter!"
Anything where they secure the perimeter?
And somebody says, "Get some rest."
"Get some rest."
We watch Jeopardy! when we eat.
But wait a minute,
Jeopardy!'s not on at eight o'clock.
-I tape it.
-You...
-I wanna know every detail of this.
-Well, one of the things he does,
and he feels free to do that...
He's watching television.
He falls asleep with his mouth open.
Well, that's what old men do.
That's a privilege of old-manness.
That's another thing,
I like to tape baseball games,
so I don't have to watch them scratch.
-Ah.
-I can move it forward.
One strike, two strikes.
Yeah, at this age, you wanna...
You don't have time.
-Just show me the hits and the catches.
-Compression, compression.
Well, that seems like a pretty nice life.
-Yeah. It's a good life. Yes.
-I have to say.
The nicest part about it,
and I mean this sincerely,
is to have a friend, and that
you guys still live near each other
and get together.
So you never go to his house?
He's an excellent driver.
Well, he's younger.
-He's four, five years younger.
-Right. Yeah, he's a kid.
[chuckles] A kid.
I haven't had bacon in an awful long time.
That's why you're 90.
I get up in the morning,
first thing I read is the obits.
-You don't do that yet. You'll see.
-No.
No, I read them. I like them.
I like that they boil
the whole guy's life down to:
"Invented the ballpoint pen spring."
If I'm not in the obit, I have breakfast.
That's my whole thing.
We really should tip her before we eat.
-We should tip before we eat?
-Yeah.
The timing of the check coming
at the end of the meal makes no sense.
'Cause that's when the food
is the least interesting to you.
-When you go in the restaurant...
-That's a great one.
You're so excited.
The appetizers and you're anticipating,
"We're gonna have this great night."
Then in the end, there's a cigarette butt
in the mashed potatoes
and then they want money for it.
And you're not hungry anymore.
And you can't understand
why you even did this whole thing.
-[Ruthie] Thank you. Please come again.
-[Jerry] Thank you.
We haven't left yet.
I had a friend who never picked up
a check without saying,
"They're charging for butter?"
[Jerry] Let me see the room
where you guys watch TV.
[Carl] Oh, here.
Mel brought these yesterday.
[Jerry] Dances with Wolves?
Boy, you're really just catching up.
-[Carl] Anyway, this is where he sits.
-Right.
[Carl] Now, when he eats, he sits here.
-[Jerry] The Mel Brooks-Carl Reiner table.
-Right, right.
-You order them on TV?
-Yes, absolutely.
-[Carl] Oh, oh, one more thing.
-[Jerry] Yeah?
-[Carl] Mel is coming over tonight.
-[Jerry] Right.
-[Carl] Would you like to come?
-[Jerry] That would be a thrill.
I would love to do that.
-[Carl] Nate 'n Al's. What do you want?
-[Jerry] You like hot tongue sandwich?
-[Carl] Yes.
-[Jerry] What does Mel like?
-[Carl] Chicken in a pot.
-[Jerry] Chicken in a pot.
-[Jerry] All right. Fantastic.
-[Carl] Okay, so 8:00.
-[Carl] See you.
-[Jerry] All right.
[man] Hey, Jerry!
[Jerry humming]
-Who's that?
-It's probably Seinfeld.
[Jerry] Hello?
-[Carl] Did you bring food?
-I did.
Hi, Mel.
Well, this looks like potato salad.
I want sandwiches, I want chicken.
Did you bring soup too?
-Look at Carl working.
-Really.
-Guy gets hit by a car, little Jewish man.
-[Jerry] Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Friend says,
"Get a pillow. Do something.
Put it under his head."
He says, "All right, are you comfortable?"
And the guy says, "I make a living."
[Jerry laughs]
I've never heard anyone
do the punchline like that.
Are you turkey or roast beef?
This thing just keeps on going.
[Mel] My doctor says don't eat salt.
-So I don't eat salt.
-Do you miss it?
No one has ever asked me that.
We're all, you know, comic...
-Luminaries.
-Yeah, luminaries, yeah.
-[Jerry] What do you think "R.B." is?
-[Mel] Roast beef.
-You're ready for Jeopardy!, I can see.
-Oh, yeah.
[Mel] What are you eating,
corned beef or pastrami?
[Jerry] The roast beef. Well, cheers.
Thank you for doing this, by the way.
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
No. That's good.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
I met a girl.
She was incredibly thin.
I took her to a restaurant.
This girl was so thin, the maître d' said,
"Check your umbrella."
I'm not making this up.
But you don't do that.
-You do characters.
-No.
-No, well, you do--
-Carl, tell him what I do.
You know, Mel,
you have never seen him work in person.
-I've always seen--
-What are you bothering him for?
No, because I will.
No, you won't.
Now I will. But do you ever work anymore?
You said you're going to Caesars.
Yeah, but you're not going to Caesars.
No, no, I'm not gonna go.
You know who I admire lately?
And not because I think he's funny.
I admire his commercial aptitude.
-[Carl] Who is that?
-Louis C.K.
[Jerry] His business acumen.
Is that what you mean?
Yes!
[Jerry] One thing for sure, Mel,
is this is getting cut out.
I'll be damned if I'm gonna sit here
hyping Louis C.K.
I don't blame you.
Get Smart. That was a show
that changed my life.
He just played it here last night.
-I got Buck Henry to come over.
-Yeah.
We watched the pilot, I said,
"Buck, just for my box set, do me a favor.
Let's watch the pilot again,
see what we can remember."
He said,
"I came up with the Cone of Silence."
Really?
"You came up with the Shoe Phone."
Oh, God, you're breaking my heart.
I love that show.
Every day, I went to Chock full o'Nuts.
And a guy started bothering me,
started pulling at my coat.
[chuckles]
Norman Steinberg.
-Jewish fella?
-Wonderful writer.
And he said, "I'm a lawyer.
I don't wanna be a lawyer.
-[Jerry chuckles]
-I wanna be a comedy writer."
So I said, "Look,
I have a show called Get Smart.
See the show and write
a Get Smart episode."
Agent 99 and 86 and...
So he did.
He wrote a couple of Get Smarts.
I don't know if they used that show,
but they used him.
It was like The Godfather.
I said, "You owe me.
[laughs]
I want you to be one of the writers
on Blazing Saddles."
That's the most amazing story
I've ever heard.
-That story doesn't usually go like that.
-[Carl and Mel] No.
To me, when you take a big chance
is when you bring
a posse of cowboys onto a soundstage
where they're doing a gay
Busby Berkeley dance number.
I saw that a few weeks ago and I thought,
-"The balls on this guy."
-[Carl] Yeah.
Were you absolutely sure
that this was gonna work?
No.
Whenever I lecture or teach
or do anything,
I say, "It's gotta please you.
If you don't laugh,
they're not gonna laugh."
-Right.
-I knew it tickled me.
I even wrote a line
where one of the gay dancers says
to a rough cowboy after he fights...
He fights with him, and he cries,
and the cowboy pets him,
and the cowboy says,
"I'm parked just behind the commissary."
Billy Wilder said,
"The reason I'm having lunch with you now
is because you had 100 cowboys
break through a set at Warner Brothers
with gay dancers."
He said, "I've been around,
I've never seen anything like that."
If Billy Wilder likes it,
I must be good, because...
-I mean, he was my god.
-You're good.
Interestingly, both of these aspects of...
Both of you guys did things
that are inside-show-business things.
A joke about the commissary,
you would think,
"Who's gonna know what a commissary is?"
[Mel] Yeah, I didn't care.
"Who's gonna know
what sitcom writers are?"
I needed a black guy to justify
our inordinate use of the N-word.
And Richie Pryor was a good friend
of mine, we used to hang out together.
So he joined us.
So I had Andrew Bergman,
Richie Pryor, Norman, and Alan Uger.
-He had a partner, a dentist...
-A lawyer and a dentist.
He never gave up being a dentist,
this guy, Alan Uger.
But he wrote comedy on the side.
He was very good.
You're kidding.
The five of us wrote Blazing Saddles.
We wrote a lot of it in New York
and then I took Norman with me.
-When I go to a comedy club...
-Why would you go to a comedy club?
-Sometimes I'm interested in attitudes.
-[Jerry] Right.
-[Mel] I smell comedy, I really do.
-Yeah.
I knew very early at the Village Vanguard
when I saw Richie Pryor.
-[Jerry] Right. Right.
-Became his pal. "This guy got it."
Chris Rock, I saw him.
Right away, I said, "He's funny."
Chris Rock, that was '96. This is 2012.
That's a long time
between guys breaking out.
This is 2012?
Holy... I have so many appoint--
I'm sorry, this is terrible to do, but I--
2012? Holy shit.
-So I had this idea...
-Right.
...about this movie
about Bialystock and Bloom,
about the ego and the id.
I mean, I was driven.
If he had spent his time with this,
he wouldn't have never done Producers.
I knew that.
I kind of knew if I got stuck in a sitcom,
it's a swamp. It's quicksand.
-You're telling me.
-[chuckles]
When The Producers came out,
the play, is that...
You thought that there was
a profound revenge for Hitler's crimes
in making fun of him?
Kenny Mars came in and read it,
and I was stunned.
[speaking in German]
I mean, he was so German.
But the very fact that he did
the definitive work against Hitler...
-[Jerry] Yes. Right.
-...in the world,
and that the musical played in Germany
-and was the biggest hit, lately.
-Really?
Yes. I won number one play.
In Berlin that season, I won
the Ernst Lubitsch Award for theater.
The very fact that you--
I don't know whether they really liked it
or they were apologizing.
-[Carl] No.
-[Mel] I'm not sure.
♪ Springtime ♪
Hank Mancini had made
an instrumental version
of "Springtime for Hitler."
[Mancini's
"Springtime for Hitler" playing]
With a... [humming] ...a little Latin.
[continues humming]
-[Carl laughs]
-[Mel mimics trumpet]
And it's playing,
and I'm with a bunch of people
in an elevator,
a nice lady, and they're swaying.
And I said,
"If they only knew the lyrics," you know?
It's challenging and it's fun.
That's why you jumped
into little clubs to say,
with brand-new material
that is bound to fail.
-[Jerry] Right.
-"How can I...
If I can get two laughs tonight."
Right. I could talk about comedy a lot,
but I think it's like talking about sex.
You can do any fancy dive you want,
it's just a foot of water.
[chuckles] That's funny.
Did you ever say this before?
-No.
-[Mel] That's good.
[Jerry] How is this possible?
That you have this mug?
"Old Jews telling jokes."
I said, "I'm an old Jew,
I'm gonna tell a joke."
This is a comedy class.
Morty sees Moshe on the street and says,
"Moshe, I heard about the fire!"
And he said, "Shh!...
[whispers] Thursday."
[Jerry and Carl laugh]
See, you get it?
See, look at all the acting I did.
-For a lousy joke!
-I saw it. To me, you're royalty.
[Mel] Oh... [clicks tongue]
I'm just a prince, I'm not a king.
I went to see Alan King at the Meadowland,
and I saw Alan King do two hours
of the most brilliant stuff
on his family, his brothers.
I met you at an Alan King show
at the Westbury Music Fair...
That's it! That's the time.
I only saw him one time in my whole life.
-That's... that's it.
-I was eight years old.
-[Mel] You're kidding. Is this true?
-Yes.
And I snuck backstage.
There was a little dressing room,
I walked in it.
You were sitting there.
Alan King was there.
I got his autograph and your autograph.
I still have it.
-Wow. Is this true?
-Yeah!
♪ I've been away from you a long time ♪
♪ I never thought ♪
♪ Somehow I feel your love is real
Near you ♪
This was a surprisingly
enjoyable experience.
-Really?
-Yes. All right.
Thanks again, Mel.
-[Mel] All right. I love you.
-Love you, too. Great to see you.
-All right, ladies and germs. Okay.
-[Jerry] All right.
Have a good night. That is a gorgeous car.
I'm glad you like it.
-What year was it?
-[Jerry] 1970.
I was five. Good night, everybody!
Wonderful working with you.
-Stop that.
-[Carl] Jerry.
What's the difference
between a Jew and a Frenchman?
A Frenchman leaves
without saying good-bye.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
-[Carl and Mel] And a Jew says good-bye
-and never leaves.
-[Jerry] Ha!
That was a great joke.
[Jeopardy theme song playing]